Guide to the Katharine Brownell Collier Papers, 1895-1977 (bulk 1904-1934)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Katharine Brownell Collier Papers
1895-1977
1904-1934
Collier, Katharine Brownell
7.3 cubic feet (8 Boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Correspondence, notebooks, manuscripts and drafts, memorabilia, artwork, publications, and photographs relating to and/or created by Katherine Brownell Collier, covering her turn-of-the-century childhood as well as her time at Vassar and her life post-graduation.
Biographical Note
Katharine Brownell Collier was born on March, 7 1887, in Lakeview, New Jersey. Her mother, Laura Brownell Collier, was a member of a prominent New England family and her father, John Austin Collier, was a scientist. While she was still a baby, the family moved to Brooklyn, where Laura Collier taught at Packer Collegiate Institute, a private, all-girls academy. Both Katharine and her older sister Elizabeth attended Packer, and then followed in their mother's footsteps and went to Vassar College.
While at Vassar, Katharine seems to have thrown herself into a number of different organizations. The Vassarions from 1905 to 1908 list her as a member of everything from the Wake Robin Club to the Christian Association to the Society of Granddaughters to the Athletic Association. She did well at Vassar and was chosen as a member of Phi Beta Kappa and the honor list for the class of 1908.
After graduating from Vassar College in 1908, Katharine moved to Bay Shore, Long Island, where she taught English and History at Bay Shore High School. In 1911 she moved back to Brooklyn, where she found a job teaching Latin and English at an annex of Bushwick High School.
Once she had returned to Brooklyn, Katharine began taking courses at Columbia University with the intention of receiving her Ph.D. However, having taken only the required history class during her sophomore year at Vassar, plus having a career, she had her work cut out for her. She was awarded her Ph.D. by Columbia in 1933. While at Columbia, her faculty advisor was Lynn Thorndike, a noted medievalist who was interested in the history of scientific thought.
Katharine Collier's Ph.D. dissertation was published by Columbia University in 1934 as part of a series of studies in history, economics, and public law edited by the faculty of the Department of Political Science. It was titled Cosmogonies of Our Fathers: Some Theories of the Seventeenth and Eighteenth Centuries. Critics referred to it as "a very thorough piece of investigation" of the clash between scientific and religious beliefs. It is still used in classrooms today. Katharine donated a copy of her work to the Vassar College Library shortly after its publication, inscribed "To my Alma Mater."
Always an admirer of the New England countryside, during the summer of 1933, Katharine built a home on some family property in Burlington, Vermont. Originally it was used as a summer home, but after her retirement in 1942 she moved there year round. Katharine never married, once referring to her state as "single blessedness." However, it appears that at least two men during her lifetime competed for her affections, Charles Harlow Harris and Raymond L. Lunt. During her final years she lived a "peaceful and unexciting life," surrounded by family and friends. She remained active, volunteering at a local hospital and participating in various organizations, from the Green Mountain Club to the League of Women Voters. She was also instrumental in bringing about the Vermont Vassar Club. In addition, she read 350 books each year, from favorite classics to detective stories. Katharine Brownell Collier died peacefully in her sleep on July 3, 1977, at the age of 90 years.
Scope and Content Note
The Katharine Brownell Collier Papers range in period from her turn-of-the-century childhood and years at Vassar College through her career as a schoolteacher and her eventual retirement. The collection's strength lies in the amount of personal correspondence she saved over the years, especially correspondence from Packer friends and her mother, Laura Brownell Collier. The section of miscellaneous correspondence to Katherine Collier includes items such as wedding invitations, greeting cards, postcards, and letters. However, any group of two or more letters was separated by the author's last name and placed with the personal correspondence to Katharine Collier. The letters in miscellaneous correspondence are from people who wrote to Collier only once, such as former pupils, colleagues, or friends of the family. The section of miscellaneous programs and pamphlets in the memorabilia series includes programs from concerts and theatrical productions that Collier apparently attended.
Different researchers may be attracted to these papers for different reasons. For example, the advertisements that each Vassar student received from the Poughkeepsie area may give some clue as to how Vassar was perceived by the citizens of Poughkeepsie. The Vassar College material is interesting because it provides a snapshot of Vassar at the turn-of-the-century, during President Taylor's administration and before the modernization program launched by President MacCracken.
The researcher should be warned, however, that these papers are weak on substance in areas, and tend to contain superficial information. The aspect of Katharine Collier's life in which this is most noticeable is her book, Cosmogonies of Our Fathers. Very little information is available concerning her research notes, data, or any preliminary manuscripts. A few notes or papers from her classes at Columbia University are there, but little else. Wherever possible, cross-references have been added to the manuscript register so the researcher is made aware of certain connections between people and organizations.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Researchers interested in the personal life of Katharine Brownell Collier are encouraged to examine the Class of 1908 Bulletins, which form part of the Class Box collection as well as the Alumnae/i Biographical Files in the Archives and Special Collections Library.
Subject Headings
Names:
Atwater, Bertha; Bourdon, Alice; Collier, Laura Brownell; Harris, Charles Harlow; Lunt, Raymond L.; Rhame, May; Stone, Mabel
Organizations:
Packer Collegiate Institute, Brooklyn; Vassar College--Alumni and alumnae; Alden Kindred of America; Blue Pencil Club (Vanderbilt University)
Places:
Vassar College; New York
Document Types:
Scrapbooks; Photographs; Postcards
VCL Categories
Family; Vassar College
Encoding Information
Encoded by Madeleine Amodio, June 2011.
Series List
- Series I: PERSONAL CORREPSONDENCE
- Series II: EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTIONS
- Series III: ORGANIZATIONS
- Series IV: NOTES AND NOTEBOOKS
- Series V: PERIODICALS AND NEWSPAPER ARTICLES
- Series VI: PHOTOGRAPHS
- Series VII: ADVERTISEMENTS SENT TO KATHARINE COLLIER
- Series VIII: POSTCARDS
- Series IX: MEMORABILIA
Container List
- SERIES I. PERSONAL CORRESPONDENCE
  - Correspondence to Katharine Brownell Collier
    - Atwater, Bertha (friend from Bay Shore High School), 1911; (14 items) (Folder 1.1)
    - Atwater, Bertha, 1912; (15 items) (Folder 1.2)
    - Atwater, Bertha, 1913; (14 items) (Folder 1.3)
    - Atwater, Bertha, January-June 1914; (9 items) (Folder 1.4)
    - Atwater, Bertha, July-December 1914; (6 items) (Folder 1.5)
    - Atwater, Bertha, 1915; (9 items) (Folder 1.6)
    - Atwater, Bertha, 1916-1927, n.d.; (6 items) (Folder 1.7)
    - Bell, Cora N. (friend from Bay Shore High School), 1910-1911; (9 items) (Folder 1.8)
    - Bell, Cora N., 1912-1913; (3 items) (Folder 1.9)
    - Bell, Cora N., 1914, n.d.; (11 items) (Folder 1.10)
    - Bell, Cora N. (friend from Bay Shore High School), see also folder 4.41
    - Bishop, Grace and Calvin (relatives of KBC), 1903-1911; (5 items) (Folder 1.11)
    - Bourdon, Alice, ca. 1918; (3 items) (Folder 1.12)
    - Bourdon, Alice, 1921-1922; (19 items) (Folder 1.13)
    - Bourdon, Alice, 1923; (22 items) (Folder 1.14)
    - Bourdon, Alice, 1924; (8 items) (Folder 1.15)
    - Bourdon, Alice, 1925; (5 items) (Folder 1.16)
    - Bourdon, Alice, 1926; (5 items) (Folder 2.1)
    - Bourdon, Alice, 1927-1929; (6 items) (Folder 2.2)
    - Bourdon, Alice, 1930-1931, n.d.; (7 items) (Folder 1.17)
    - Bourdon, Alice: see also: Fatherless Children of France, folders 3.105-3.106, *most correspondence in French
    - Correspondence re: Alice Bourdon, 1925; (1 item) (Folder 1.18)
    - Bushnell, Ethel (friend from Bay Shore High School), 1914-1915; (3 items) (Folder 1.19)
    - Bushnell, Ethel, 1942-1943; (11 items) (Folder 2.3)
    - Bushnell, Ethel, 1944-1945, n.d.; (14 items) (Folder 1.20)
    - Bushnell, Ethel (friend from Bay Shore High School), see also folder 4.67
    - Coffin, Philip L., 1928-1932, n.d.; (7 items) (Folder 1.21)
    - Collier, Elizabeth Brownell (sister of KBC), 1908-1912; (7 items) (Folder 1.22)
    - Collier, Elizabeth Brownell, n.d.; (3 items) (Folder 1.23)
    - Collier, John A. (father of KBC), 1905-1906; (11 items) (Folder 1.24)
    - Collier, John A., 1907-1911, n.d.; (4 items) (Folder 1.25)
    - Collier, Laura Brownell (mother of KBC), 1905; (10 items) (Folder 1.26)
    - Collier, Laura Brownell, 1906; (9 items) (Folder 1.27)
    - Collier, Laura Brownell, May-October 1907; (23 items) (Folder 1.28)
    - Collier, Laura Brownell, November 1907; (11 items) (Folder 1.29)
    - Collier, Laura Brownell, December 1907; (25 items) (Folder 1.30)
    - Collier, Laura Brownell, January 1908; (21 items) (Folder 1.31)
    - Collier, Laura Brownell, February 1908; (16 items) (Folder 1.32)
    - Collier, Laura Brownell, March 1908; (21 items) (Folder 1.33)
    - Collier, Laura Brownell, April 1908; (7 items) (Folder 1.34)
    - Collier, Laura Brownell, May 1908; (17 items) (Folder 1.35)
    - Collier, Laura Brownell, 1911-1913, n.d.; (19 items) (Folder 1.36)
    - DeFlaude, Charles, 1925-1928, n.d.; (11 items) (Folder 1.37)
    - Dench, Ernest and Iva, 1928-1931, n.d.; (5 items) (Folder 1.38)
    - Dench, Ernest and Iva, see also: Blue Pencil Club, folders 5.6-5.24
    - Denman, Helen, 1902-1903; (7 items) (Folder 1.39)
    - Dixon, Robert S., 1917; (11 items) (Folder 1.40)
    - Dixon, Robert S., 1918-1919; (5 items) (Folder 1.41)
    - Eichinger, Romain *correspondence is in French, March-July 1917; (9 items) (Folder 1.42)
    - Eichinger, Romain, October-December 1917; (11 items) (Folder 1.43)
    - Eichinger, Romain, January-April 1918; (8 items) (Folder 1.44)
    - Eichinger, Romain, May-August 1918; (8 items) (Folder 1.45)
    - Eichinger, Romain, 1919-1921; (6 items) (Folder 1.46)
    - Eichinger, Romain, 1926-1931, n.d.; (9 items) (Folder 1.47)
    - Gross, Elizabeth (friend from Bay Shore High School), 1911-1912; (4 items) (Folder 1.48)
    - Harris, Charles Harlow, 1911-1912; (6 items) (Folder 1.49)
    - Harris, Charles Harlow, 1913; (6 items) (Folder 1.50)
    - Harris, Charles Harlow, January-April 1914; (6 items) (Folder 1.51)
    - Harris, Charles Harlow, May 1914; (7 items) (Folder 1.52)
    - Harris, Charles Harlow, June-December 1914; (6 items) (Folder 1.53)
    - Harris, Charles Harlow, March-July 1915; (7 items) (Folder 1.54)
    - Harris, Charles Harlow, August-October 1915; (6 items) (Folder 1.55)
    - Harris, Charles Harlow, 1916; (9 items) (Folder 1.56)
    - Harris, Charles Harlow, 1917-1918; (9 items) (Folder 1.57)
    - Harris, Charles Harlow, see also folder 3.25
    - Harris, Gertrude (sister of Charles Harris), 1914-1915; (3 items) (Folder 1.58)
    - Hobson, Mary, 1933, n.d.; (5 items) (Folder 1.59)
    - Holbrook, Edith, 1909-1915; (6 items) (Folder 1.60)
    - Ives, Edna, 1907-1911; (6 items) (Folder 1.61)
    - Jaklitsch, Frank, 1922-1926; (10 items) (Folder 1.62)
    - Jaklitsch, Frank, 1927; (4 items) (Folder 1.63)
    - Jaklitsch, Frank, 1928-1933, n.d.; (7 items) (Folder 1.64)
    - Jaklitsch, Frank, see also folder 4.67
    - Jameson, Ruth, 1912-1913; (3 items) (Folder 1.65)
    - Karagueziau, A.H., 1906-1907; (2 items) (Folder 1.66)
    - King, Annie G. VC 1909, 1908-1909; (10 items) (Folder 1.67)
    - King, Annie G., 1910-1914; (5 items) (Folder 1.68)
    - King, Annie G., 1916-1928, n.d.; (8 items including 1 fragile item in mylar sheets) (Folder 1.69)
    - King, Annie G. VC 1909, see also folder 4.42
    - Kingsbury, Peggy, 1918-1925, n.d.; (8 items) (Folder 1.70)
    - Laval, Marie, *most correspondence in French, 1918-1920; (6 items) (Folder 1.71)
    - Laval, Marie, see also: Fatherless Children of France, folders 3.105-3.106, *most correspondence in French
    - Loder, Marion (teacher at Packer, 1887-1914), 1895, n.d.; (4 items) (Folder 1.72)
    - Lunt, Raymond L., 1906; (14 items) (Folder 2.4)
    - Lunt, Raymond L., January-March 1907; (10 items) (Folder 2.5)
    - Lunt, Raymond L., April-July 1907; (15 items) (Folder 2.6)
    - Lunt, Raymond L., August-October 1907; (14 items) (Folder 2.7)
    - Lunt, Raymond L., November-December 1907; (15 items) (Folder 2.8)
    - Lunt, Raymond L., January-March 1908; (16 items) (Folder 2.9)
    - Lunt, Raymond L., April-June 1908; (16 items) (Folder 2.10)
    - Lunt, Raymond L., July-September 1908; (15 items) (Folder 2.11)
    - Lunt, Raymond L., October-December 1908; (9 items) (Folder 2.12)
    - Lunt, Raymond L., January-August 1909; (21 items) (Folder 2.13)
    - Lunt, Raymond L., September-December 1909; (9 items) (Folder 2.14)
    - Lunt, Raymond L., 1910; (4 items) (Folder 2.15)
    - Lunt, Raymond L., (1 fragment) (Folder 2.16)
    - Lunt, Raymond L. see also folder 4.43
    - Martin, Marjorie (friend from Packer), 1901-1905; (4 items) (Folder 2.17)
    - Martin, Marjorie, 1906-1907, n.d.; (9 items) (Folder 2.18)
    - Martin, Marjorie (friend from Packer) see also folders 3.27, 4.49
    - Morton, Pearl and James, 1928-1944, n.d.; (9 items) (Folder 2.19)
    - Morton, Pearl and James see also: Blue Pencil Club, folders 5.6-5.24
    - "Nannie,", 1899; (1 item) (Folder 2.20)
    - Nicosia, Josephine, 1928-1930; (6 items) (Folder 2.21)
    - Nicosia, Josephine, 1932-1933, n.d.; (3 items) (Folder 2.22)
    - Orinsbee, Mary Royce, 1905; (3 items) (Folder 2.23)
    - Palmer, Madge (friend from Packer), 1903-1905; (10 items) (Folder 2.24)
    - Palmer, Madge, 1906-1914; (8 items) (Folder 2.25)
    - Pearce, Viola Walker (friend from Bay Shore High School), 1910-1912; (9 items) (Folder 2.26)
    - Pearce, Viola Walker, 1913-1915, n.d.; (11 items) (Folder 2.27)
    - Poléntier, Simone, 1920-1921; (3 items) (Folder 2.28)
    - Powell, Mary B., 1902-1903, n.d.; (3 items) (Folder 2.29)
    - Pullis, Jessica Kennedy (friend from Bay Shore High School), 1911-1912; (8 items) (Folder 2.30)
    - Pullis, Jessica Kennedy, 1914, n.d.; (5 items) (Folder 2.31)
    - Pullis, Jessica Kennedy (friend from Bay Shore High School) see also folder 4.45
    - Rathjen, Ruth, 1929-1965; (5 items) (Folder 2.32)
    - Rhame, Eleanora "May" Davis (friend from Packer), 1904; (2 items) (Folder 2.33)
    - Rhame, May, 1906; (7 items) (Folder 2.34)
    - Rhame, May, 1907; (7 items) (Folder 1.73)
    - Rhame, May, 1908; (6 items) (Folder 1.74)
    - Rhame, May, January-April 1909; (10 items) (Folder 1.75)
    - Rhame, May, May-December 1909; (8 items) (Folder 1.76)
    - Rhame, May, 1910; (5 items) (Folder 1.77)
    - Rhame, May, March-August 1911; (3 items) (Folder 1.78)
    - Rhame, May, October-December 1911; (5 items) (Folder 1.79)
    - Rhame, May, 1912; (3 items) (Folder 1.80)
    - Rhame, May, 1913-1914; (4 items) (Folder 1.81)
    - Rhame, May, 1917-1918; (4 items) (Folder 1.82)
    - Rhame, May, 1930-1933; (5 items) (Folder 1.83)
    - Rhame, May, 1934-1944; (4 items) (Folder 1.84)
    - Rhame, May, n.d.; (8 items) (Folder 1.85)
    - Rhame, May, n.d.; (7 items) (Folder 1.86)
    - Rhame, May, n.d.; (4 items) (Folder 1.87)
    - Rhame, Eleanora "May" Davis (friend from Packer), see also folder 4.45
    - Rhame, Sophie May (daughter of May Rhame), 1926-1933; (6 items) (Folder 1.88)
    - Rhame, William (son of May Rhame), 1927-1933; (6 items) (Folder 1.89)
    - Rhame, William (son of May Rhame) see also folder 4.47
    - Safford, Anne and Helen, 1900-1906; (6 items) (Folder 1.90)
    - Safford, Anne and Helen, 1907-1925, n.d.; (11 items) (Folder 1.91)
    - Smith, Clarence E., 1912-1913; (3 items) (Folder 1.92)
    - Smith, Ruth Carey, 1928-1943; (9 items) (Folder 1.93)
    - Smith, Ruth Carey, 1944-1968; (4 items) (Folder 1.94)
    - Smith, Ruth Carey, see also folder 4.49
    - Stone, Mabel (friend from Packer, Smith Class of 1909), 1902-1903; (15 items) (Folder 1.95)
    - Stone, Mabel, January-August 1904; (13 items) (Folder 1.96)
    - Stone, Mabel, September-December 1904; (7 items) (Folder 1.97)
    - Stone, Mabel, January-May 1905; (7 items) (Folder 3.1)
    - Stone, Mabel, August-December 1905; (12 items) (Folder 3.2)
    - Stone, Mabel, January-July 1906; (11 items) (Folder 3.3)
    - Stone, Mabel, August-December 1906; (14 items) (Folder 3.4)
    - Stone, Mabel, 1907; (9 items) (Folder 3.5)
    - Stone, Mabel, 1908; (6 items) (Folder 3.6)
    - Stone, Mabel, 1909-1911; (9 items) (Folder 3.7)
    - Stone, Mabel, n.d.; (11 items) (Folder 3.8)
    - Stone, Mabel (friend from Packer, Smith Class of 1909) see also folder 3.28
    - Sullivan, Ruth, 1914-1918, n.d.; (9 items) (Folder 2.35)
    - Talmage, David "Budd" Jr., 1906; (3 items) (Folder 2.36)
    - Vinçon, Roger, 1918-1921; (5 items) (Folder 2.37)
    - Vinçon, Roger, see also Fatherless Children of France, folders 3.105-3.106, 4.81
    - [Wales, Theodosia H.] VC 1906, 1906-1907; (2 items) (Folder 2.38)
    - Webb, Ethel, 1919; (6 items) (Folder 2.39)
    - Webb, Ethel, see also folder 4.65
    - West, Ethel, 1899-1903; (8 items) (Folder 2.40)
    - West, Ethel, February-May 1906; (11 items) (Folder 2.41)
    - West, Ethel, July-December 1906; (4 items) (Folder 2.42)
    - West, Ethel, 1907-1908; (9 items) (Folder 2.43)
    - West, Ethel, 1909-1915, n.d.; (6 items) (Folder 2.44)
    - West, Ethel, see also folder 4.48
    - Wheeler, Loraine H. (cousin of KBC) includes one letter re: Elizabeth Collier, 1931-1969; (7 items) (Folder 2.45)
    - Wheeler, Loraine H. (cousin of KBC) includes one letter re: Elizabeth Collier, see also folders 4.38, 4.63
    - Wood, Frank R., 1930-1932; (5 items) (Folder 2.46)
    - Wood, Frank R., see also: Blue Pencil Club, folders 5.6-5.24
    - Woodbury, Ella A., 1913-1915, n.d.; (7 items) (Folder 2.47)
    - Wright, Anna Collier (relative of KBC), 1903; (1 item) (Folder 2.48)
    - Wright, Donald Collier (cousin of KBC), 1898-1906; (3 items) (Folder 2.49)
    - Wright, Donald Collier (cousin of KBC) see also folder 4.67
    - Wright, Eleanora F., 1912; (4 items) (Folder 2.50)
    - Wright, Eleanora F., 1913-1918; (7 items) (Folder 2.51)
    - Wright, Eleanora F., see also folder 3.30
    - Miscellaneous Letters, 1895-1900; (11 items) (Folder 3.9)
    - Miscellaneous Letters, 1902-1903; (8 items) (Folder 3.10)
    - Miscellaneous Letters, 1904-1908; (4 items) (Folder 3.11)
    - Miscellaneous Letters, 1909-1918; (12 items) (Folder 3.12)
    - Miscellaneous Letters, 1919-1925; (8 items) (Folder 3.13)
    - Miscellaneous Letters, 1927-1928; (8 items) (Folder 3.14)
    - Miscellaneous Letters, 1929-1930; (6 items) (Folder 3.15)
    - Miscellaneous Letters, 1931-1965; (10 items) (Folder 3.16)
    - Miscellaneous Letters, n.d.; (6 items) (Folder 3.17)
    - Thurp, E. H. to Chauncey [Brownell], 1925; (1 item) (Folder 3.31)
    - Miscellaneous Greeting Cards and Postcards, 1905-1914; (8 items) (Folder 3.18)
    - Miscellaneous Greeting Cards and Postcards, 1919-1945; (7 items) (Folder 3.19)
    - Miscellaneous Greeting Cards and Postcards, (8 items) (Folder 3.20)
    - Miscellaneous Greeting Cards and Postcards, (7 items) (Folder 3.21)
    - Miscellaneous Calling Cards, 1906-1910, n.d.; (9 items) (Folder 3.22)
    - Wedding Invitations, n.d.; (9 items) (Folder 3.23)
    - Correspondence to Katharine Brownell Collier (Folder 4.76)
    - Correspondence to KBC: Miscellaneous Notes (Folder 3.120)
    - Correspondence to KBC: Miscellaneous (Folder 3.121)
    - Correspondence to KBC: From Friend in Bayshore, LI (Folder 3.122)
    - Correspondence to KBC: Vassar College (Folder 3.123)
    - Correspondence to KBC: Vassar College (Folder 4.91)
    - Correspondence to KBC: South Willard Street (Folder 4.92)
    - Correspondence to KBC: De Kalb Avenue (Folder 4.93)
    - Correspondence to KBC: De Kalb Avenue (Folder 4.94)
    - Correspondence to KBC: De Kalb Avenue (Folder 4.95)
    - Correspondence to KBC: De Kalb Avenue (Folder 4.96)
    - Correspondence to KBC: De Kalb Avenue (Folder 6.1)
    - Correspondence to KBC: De Kalb Avenue (Folder 6.2)
    - Correspondence to KBC: Vassar College (Folder 6.3)
    - Correspondence to KBC: Letters from VC Friends While in College (Folder 6.4)
    - Correspondence to KBC: Letters from VC Friends While in College (Folder 6.5)
    - Correspondence to KBC: Letters from VC Friends While in College (Folder 6.6)
    - Correspondence to KBC: Letters from Vassar Friends after College (Folder 6.7)
    - Correspondence to KBC: Vassar College (Folder 6.8)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence to KBC (Folder 6.9)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence to KBC (Folder 6.10)
  - Correspondence from or about Katharine Brownell Collier
    - Grand Central Station, 1908; (1 item) (Folder 3.24)
    - Harris, Charles Harlow, 1914-1918; (6 items, 1 fragment) (Folder 3.25)
    - Langman, Jeanette, 1914; (1 item) (Folder 3.26)
    - Martin, Marjorie, 1941; (2 items) (Folder 3.27)
    - Stone, Mabel, 1903; (5 items, 1 fragment) (Folder 3.28)
    - Unknown persons, 1918-1926, n.d.; (6 items, 1 fragment) (Folder 3.29)
    - Wright, Eleanora, 1913; (1 item) (Folder 3.30)
    - Thurp, E.H. to Chauncey [Brownell], 1925; (1 item) (Folder 3.31)
    - Correspondence from KBC (Folder 3.119)
- SERIES II. EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTIONS
  - Packer Collegiate Institute
    - see also folders 5.45-5.50, 4.3, 4.46, 4.17
    - Report Cards, 1895-1898; (8 items) (Folder 2.52)
    - Report Cards and teachers' comments, 1899-1900, n.d.; (11 items) (Folder 2.53)
    - The Packer Alumna, June 1906; (TS, 16 p.) (Folder 2.54)
    - The Packer Alumna, December 1906; (TS, 18 p.) (Folder 2.55)
    - The Packer Alumna, December 1907; (TS, 18 p.) (Folder 2.56)
    - The Packer Alumna, June 1908; (TS, 21 p.) (Folder 2.57)
    - The Packer Alumna, June 1942; (TS, 29 p.) (Folder 2.58)
    - Annual Report of the President to the Board of Trustees, 1945-1946; (TS, 21 p.) (Folder 2.59)
    - Packer Associate Alumnae re: membership and dues, 1906; (4 items) (Folder 2.60)
    - Packer Association Alumnae events; including songbook of Packer songs, 1906-1909, n.d.; (7 items) (Folder 2.61)
    - Correspondence From Truman J. Backus, President of Packer, 1902-1904; (2 items) (Folder 2.62)
    - Other Packer-related correspondence, 1906-1907; (5 items) (Folder 2.63)
    - Programs-- "Little Women" role of Beth played by KBC, May 1901; (6 items) (Folder 2.64)
    - Programs-- Other programs, 1903-1904; (7 items) (Folder 2.65)
    - Programs-- Packer's Centennial Celebration, 1944/1945; (7 items) (Folder 2.66)
    - Programs-- Packer Collegiate Institute (Folder 6.13)
  - Vassar College
    - see also folders 4.1, 4.73, 3.81, 3.111, 5.125-5.128
    - Entrance Record, ca. 1904; (1 item) (Folder 2.67)
    - Examination Questions — Freshman Greek, Freshman English, and Solid Geometry, 1905; (5 items) (Folder 2.68)
    - Examination Questions — Intro to Philosophy, General Biology, Principles of Economics, A French, 1907; (4 items) (Folder 2.69)